he guys let's say we wanted to find the
rectangle where the perimeter was equal
to 420 and the area was equal to 69 we
need to find the base and the height
that would make this true if you want to
try it on your own pause it right now
cuz I'm going to solve it in 3 2 1 so
let's called the base X and the height y
we know that the perimeter is going to
be 2 X's + 2 y and that needs to equal
420 and the area is going to be the base
time height or in other words x y and
that needs to equal 69 so right now we
have two variables X and Y and we have
two equations let's solve for x and y so
I'm going to clean things up a little
bit on top we can simplify things by
dividing everything by two and on bottom
we can get the Y by itself by dividing
both sides by X up here on the left hand
side these twos will cancel each other
out and on the right hand side 420 / 2
is 210 and then down here on the left
hand side these X's will cancel each
other out so we're left with Y is equal
to 69 /x let's take this X+ y = 210 and
copy it down here and we know that Y is
equal to 69 /x so in the place of this y
let's plug in 69x and I don't really
like fractions so let's get rid of this
X in the denominator we can do that by
multiplying both sides of the equation
by X on the left hand side this x will
distribute to give us x * x and x * 69
/x and on the right hand side we get 210
* x x * X gives us x^2 and this X and
this x will cancel each other out this
is a quadratic so I want to set it equal
to zero so let's subtract 210x from both
sides on the right hand side these will
cancel each other out so it's equal to
zero and on the left hand hand side we
have x^2 - 210x + 69 now let's solve
this using the quadratic formula the
leading coefficient is a one so both of
these A's are equal to 1 and then the
second coefficient is -210 so in the
place of both of these B's we can plug
in -210 and last the C is equal to 69
now we can clean this up -210 is equal
to postive 210 -210 2 is equal to
44,100 and 4 * 1 * 69 is = to 2
276 and on bottom 2 * 1 is equal to 2
44,100 - 276 is equal to
43824 and
43824 can we split up into 16 *
2739 and then we can give each of these
their own square root 16 is a perfect
square so we can change this into four
and this two in the denominator can be
split up for both of these terms 210 / 2
is 105 and 4 < TK 2739 / 2 is equal to 2
< tkk 2739 and now we have our values of
X they're 105 plus or- 2 < TK 2739 and
this plus or minus can be split up into
two different numbers we have the plus
version and the minus version and now
for each of these X's we have to find
the corresponding y let's use this x + y
is equal to 210 we can subtract X from
both sides these two x's will cancel
each other out and now we know that Y is
equal to 210 - x so in the place of both
these y's let's plug in 210 - X for the
first box X is equal to this so let's
plug this in for x and for the second
box X is equal to this so let's plug in
this for X both of these are positive so
the negative will make them both
negative and aside these parentheses the
first one's positive and the second
one's negative after we subtract they're
going to switch the first one will be
negative and the second one will be
positive now for the first box 210 - 105
is equal to 105 so we have the value of
y that corresponds to this X and then
for the second box 210 - 5 is 105 so we
have the corresponding value of y for
this value of x so all these boxes are
doing are just swapping the X and the Y
so we can just get rid of the second box
so now we have the value of our base is
105 + 2 < TK 2739 and the value of our
height is 105 - 2 < TK 2739 so now we
can put these values in for the base and
the height and create a problem that
says find the area and perimeter and if
you want to see the video solving this
problem the link is in the description
how exciting